Vijayasarathi Balasubramanian

Data Engineer at AT&T

vijayasarathib@gmail.com

Summary

8+ years of technical and functional experience in Information Management, specializing in data warehousing, enterprise data management, and business intelligence solutions. Proven capability in leading all stages of system development efforts, including requirements definition, system analysis & design, architecture, development, testing, implementation and operational support. Comfortable working in onsite-offshore project model; experience in Waterfall & Agile methodologies. Worked in the domains of Supply Chain, Telecommunications, Banking and Retail. Expert in ETL tool Ab Initio. Specialties: • Business Intelligence/ Data Warehousing • Data Integration/Data Quality • System analysis and Design Technical: Ab-initio (GDE, EME, Continuous Flows, Web EME), Talend, Hadoop, Hive, Unix Shell Scripting, Oracle, DB2, Teradata, Tivoli Workload Scheduler, PL/SQL, SQL.

Experience

Data Engineer at AT&T

October 2014 - Present (7 months)

DWH Consultant at Tata Consultancy Services

June 2010 - October 2014 (4 years 5 months)

Data Integration Specialist at The Home Depot

April 2009 - October 2014 (5 years 7 months)

IT Analyst - BI at Tata Consultancy Services

January 2009 - May 2010 (1 year 5 months)

Assistant System Engineer at Tata Consultancy Services

July 2006 - January 2009 (2 years 7 months)

BI Developer at BT Global Services

September 2006 - November 2008 (2 years 3 months)

Languages

English

Tamil Hindi

(Native or bilingual proficiency)

(Native or bilingual proficiency)

(Elementary proficiency)

Certifications

Cloudera Certified Hadoop Developer (CCD-410)

Cloudera July 2014

Data Integration Consultant

Talend March 2014

Project Management Professional(PMP)

Project Management Institute July 2013

Big Data Consultant

Talend May 2014

SCJP 1.5

Sun Microsystems April 2007

Teradata Basics V2R5 Certification - NR0-011

Teradata February 2008

Teradata SQL V2R5 Certification

Teradata February 2010

MongoDB for Python Developers

MongoDB, Inc. December 2014

Intro to Data Science

Udacity September 2009

Skills & Expertise

Unix Shell Scripting

Ab Initio

Teradata

Databases

Leadership

PL/SQL

Java

ETL

Data Warehousing

Quality Center

Business Intelligence Tools

Oracle

Unix

Data Modeling

Informatica

DB₂

Requirements Analysis

SDLC

Agile Methodologies

SQL

Systems Analysis

Business Intelligence

Data Integration Shell Scripting

Education

Thiagarajar College of Engineering

Eng, Electrical, 2002 - 2006

Activities and Societies: Editor for an Intra Departmental magazine - Minnalai Coordinator for ELESYTEC-A National level technical symposium

Vijayasarathi Balasubramanian

Data Engineer at AT&T

vijayasarathib@gmail.com



Contact Vijayasarathi on LinkedIn